# **Pavlos Karalis**

I'm a Full-Stack Developer capable of tackling a project from multiple-perspectives, and can dependably deliver tailored, maintainable results via a crafted approach. Furthermore, with 8 years of prior experience as a DC metro area event photographer, resourcefulness, professionalism, and ingenuity have all become second nature.

Rockville, Maryland
(301) 642-5129
pavloskaralis@gmail.com
Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### **DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE | DEVELOPER PORTFOLIO**

# **Software Engineering Fellow** — *General Assembly*

2019 - 2020

700 Hour course on Full-Stack Development, Frameworks, and APIs.

Traveler: Full-Stack trip planner with shared user model Project

React, Redux-Thunk, Rails, PostgreSQL, Bcrypt README.md

Spell ✓ It: Full-Stack spell checker with interactive text Project

Angular, Spring Boot, MySQL, Regex, SCSS README.md

Appstractor: Full-stack image filter application/gallery Project
Express, Mongoose, EJS, jQuery, Unsplash API README.md

**Go-Fish:** 2 to 4 player DOM game against programmed AI Project jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Photoshop README.md

### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

## **Real Estate Photographer** — *Redfin*

2018 - PRESENT

- Capturing residential properties for Redfin's Maryland region.
- Onboarding and mentoring new photographer employees.

## **Freelance Photographer** — Pavlos Karalis Photography

2012 - 2019

- Captured headshots, events, and weddings for various clientele.
- Hired and managed assistant photographers and videographers.

## **Event Photographer** — *EPNAC*

2015 - 2018

- Captured corporate/government events with prominent speakers.
- Oversaw team travel assignments in cities across the country.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Corcoran College of Art and Design** — BFA Photography

#### **Frontend**

React

Redux-Thunk Styled Components

Angular TypeScript jQuery

Javascript ES6

HTML5 CSS3 SCSS Bootstrap

#### **Backend**

Node.js Express EJS PHP Laravel Java SpringBoot

Ruby Rails MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB

ISON Web Tokens

#### Other

Github Postman Trello

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro